# José Enciso

#### **CONTACT**

Birstall, Leicester +44 775 270 1658 josejefloen@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/joseenciso-88/

linkedin.com/in/joseenciso-88 github.com/joseenciso

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Jquery

JSON

Bootstrap 4 & 5

React.JS

Node.JS

Python

Flask

Django

AWS S3

Git

GitHub

### **AWARDS**

Software Development Diploma

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish (Native)

English

German, Level A1

#### **PROFILE**

Passionate for technology Electrical Technician in Digital Systems with 5 years experience in the industry highly motivated, hardworking individual striving to become a full stack developer graduated from Code Institute Software Development Bootcamp. Always learning something new, currently Im experimenting with RactJS and node.js.

I hold my own domain name for my personal portfolio website "www.joseenciso.co.uk/" which still under construction as I'm experimenting with new technologies and techniques.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Code Institute, Online — Software Developer

January 2019 - April 2021

Course credit-rated by Edinburgh Napier university broken into 4 milestones projects, where I learnt the frontend technologies such as HTML, CSS, Javascript and the usages the frameworks like bootstrap and jquery till the backend with Python and Flask and Django as web frameworks, databases as SQL and MongoDB, deploying two of the milestones projects on Heroku, uses of control version with Git, GitHub and the AWS S3 service to store images.

# **Open University of Mexico**, Mexico — Software Development

Unconclude

I started the first year of Software Development and had to leave the career for some difficulties back in that time.

### **PROJECTS**

#### Abel Pineda Consultant — Consultant Website

Static single page website for a friend to help him to boost his project as a restaurant and pub's consultant to keep my knowledge as fresh as possible and challenging myself to learn more. The technologies to be used for this project are HTML, CSS, Javascript and jQuery on the frontend.

https://github.com/joseenciso/abelpineda

https://www.abelpinedaconsultant.co.uk/

# Backpocket — eCommerce

MVC (Model-View-Controller) FullStack eCommerce project hosted in Heroku developed with python and the web framework Django in the back-end and for the front-end Bootstrap 5, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Due to the nature of Django the SQL database is build with the ORM and the dataset is in JSON notation.

This project deployed in Heroku, the images are stored in Amazon AWS S3 and also integrates Stripe for

https://backpocket-store.herokuapp.com/

https://github.com/joseenciso/Backpocket

# Bottleneck — Video Games Blog

FullStack project deployed in Heroku that works with Python's web framework Flask in the BackEnd, MongoDB as a database connected to AtlasDB to store images and text, and in the FrontEnd the technologies are HTML, CSS and Bootstrap 4.

https://bottleneck-gaming.herokuapp.com/

https://github.com/joseenciso/bottleneck

#### **Live Band** — *Artist's show finder*

This project is focused on using Javascript and JQuery to retrieve data from an external Rest- API and presenting them into a user interface.

https://joseenciso.github.io/Live-Band/

https://github.com/joseenciso/Live-Band

### www.joseenciso.co.uk — Portfolio website

This is my very first project, this project is intended to change as I am getting experience with the technologies and the trends, adding little by little a better UI/UX, better HTML, CSS and Javascript implementation and adding Backend functionalities in the near future. Currently I'm experimenting with ReactJS and with the help of gh-pages a nodejs application that builds the reactjs projects into static web applications making it possible to be hosted in github-pages.

https://joseenciso.github.io/Jose-Enciso/

https://github.com/joseenciso/Jose-Enciso

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### BPW Limited, Leicester— Operator

August 2021 - Currently

# **Hammonds Furniture**, Hinkley — *Operator*

Sept 2018 - May 2021

#### Pizza Hut, Leicester— Foodie

Dec 2014 - Oct 2019

#### Sanmina-SCI, Guadalajara-México— Electronic Technician

Oct 2012 - Mar 2014